Objectives

In advertising ... to use my experience, conceptual skills, copywriting and direction abilities to build brands and help sell products and services.

In life ... to be a committed husband, father, friend and colleague.

A collaborative approach

Whether working in-house, in an advertising agency or as a free-lancer, I've been blessed to produce advertising creative for many great clients in various industries. I have gained a great appreciation for working with people who are good at what they do in their given fields. I respect their knowledge and rely on it as I develop creative strategies and concepts on their behalf. I don't assume I know better than they what best represents them or their product offerings to their audiences. Rather, I learn from my clients. Then, using my experience and creative abilities, I present creative options, opinions and perspectives for us to consider as a team. Sometimes I will encourage my clients to challenge their own assumptions. As iron sharpens iron, being openminded to different perspectives can bring out the best results.

Professional Experience

2005 to present Revcom Advertising & Design

Develop creative concepts and work with creative team and outside vendors to produce package design, print and digital advertising, radio spots, videos, sales materials, product literature, social media creative and website content for a variety of clients.

Examples of clients and brands served:

Ruiz Foods® – America's leading manufacturer of frozen Mexican food

El Monterey® – America's #1 selling brand of frozen Mexican food

Tornados® – America's #1 selling roller grill snack

Plantivore[™] – new plant-based burrito brand

Artisan Bistro® – high-end frozen burrito brand

Not Your Nonna's™ – Italian-style hot-to-go food brand

Wawona Frozen Foods® – frozen fruit company serving retail and foodservice

Aniln Windows & Doors - California-based manufacturer of replacement windows and doors

Murphy Bank – Central California bank

2000 to 2005 Panagraph, Inc. / Creative Director and Senior Writer

Developed creative concepts for variety of clients in diverse industries and all media. Wrote everything from corporation names and taglines to multimedia ad campaigns. Worked with creative staff to see creative execution through to fruition. Presented creative work to existing and to potential clients.

1998 to 2000 Michael J. Insalaco / Free-lance

Served as free-lance creative director and copywriter for variety of clients.

1997 to 1998 Val Print Companies / Marketing Director, Creative Director

Served as in-house marketing director for network of printing companies. Served as creative director and copywriter for clients not represented by agencies.

1996 Blue Cross of Washington and Alaska / Advertising and Promotions Team Leader

Oversaw in-house talent and advertising agency in development of all advertising and promotion for large Northwest health insurance company.

1991 to 1996 ValuCare & Priority Health Services / Communications Coordinator

Developed creative concepts and copy for all image-related communications. Oversaw external advertising agency in development of all advertising and public relations efforts for mid-sized regional HMO and health management company.

1989 to 1991 Boling Associates / Creative services

Performed all creative services, from copywriting to print production, for all clients of regional advertising agency.

Education

1989 BA from California State University, Fresno

Major: Advertising, School of Journalism

Minor: Radio & Television, School of Communications